<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Casino Analytics Professional Cooperative: CAP-COOP</title>
    <description>  Casino Analytics Professional Cooperative (CAP-COOP) is an educational and networking community comprised of enthusiastic technology and analytic specialists employed in the casino gaming industry.
</description>
    <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/</link>
     
         <atom:link href="http://casinoanalytics.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 21:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 21:19:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Hugo v0.40.2</generator>
    
    
      <item>
        <title>CAP-COOP to attend Casino Mktg &amp;amp; Tech Conf.</title>
        <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I&amp;amp;rsquo;m looking forward to attending next week&amp;amp;rsquo;s &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://www.casinomarketingconf.com&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Casino Marketing &amp;amp;amp; Technology Conference&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; at Caesars Palace, to spread the word about CAP-COOP. This is an annual conference produced by &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://www.casinojournal.com/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Casino Journal&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; magazine, bringing together thought leaders in the industry. The attendees are individuals with a specific interest in seeing the newest technology products available and hearing from experts in the field, and (hopefully) push to make positive changes within their own companies by adopting technology and analytics in intelligent ways.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I&amp;amp;rsquo;m most excited to hear the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://www.casinomarketingconf.com/index.php/conference/casino-technology-marketing-conference#wednesday-july-18&amp;#34;&amp;gt;debate&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; moderated by Dennis Conrad, entitled &amp;amp;ldquo;Can Slot Players Tell a Loose Slot from a Tight Slot?&amp;amp;rdquo; A little background here&amp;amp;hellip; In April 2017 GGB Magazine &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://ggbmagazine.com/article/that-winning-feeling/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;published a study&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; by Dr. Anthony Lucas of UNLV and Dr. Katherine Spilde of San Diego State. I read the article, and found a lot of aspects of their study to be troublesome, and their results to be unreliable. I published a &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://thehousesometimeswins.com/severely-flawed-slot-machine-experiment-unsurprisingly-reaches-incorrect-conclusion-8f02f869003c&amp;#34;&amp;gt;rebuttal&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; online, but not having a lot of readers, didn&amp;amp;rsquo;t get (or expect) much traction. I didn&amp;amp;rsquo;t even realize until just a few months ago, but multiple people also disagreed with the original article. &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://ggbmagazine.com/article/loose-or-tight/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Two additional rebuttals&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; were published in GGB and &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/players-perceiving-tight-slots-dennis-conrad&amp;#34;&amp;gt;another&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, by Dennis Conrad, in Casino Journal. Well, this battle royale will play out on Wed., July 18 at 1:30 when Dr. Lucas, along with collegue Dr. Ashok Singh, debate the matter with Buddy Frank and Michael Meczka, authors of the GGB rebuttals. Mr. Conrad will moderate. This is going to be a very fascinating, passionate debate!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Casino Marketing &amp;amp;amp; Tech Conference also coincides with the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://casinomarketingconf.com/index.php/conference/host-development-conference&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Host Development Conference&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; on Mon-Tues, and a &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://www.casinomarketingconf.com/index.php/conference/mobile-experience-and-engagement-training-workshop&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Mobile Experience Workshop&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; on Tuesday as well. A really great week arranged by CJ!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I&amp;amp;rsquo;d also like to thank Casino Journal for giving CAP-COOP an opportunity to be represented at the conference and to invite attendees and their colleagues to join our group. Much appreciated!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-07-12 21:19:20 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
        <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/07/12/going-to-cmtc-20180712.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/07/12/going-to-cmtc-20180712.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wrap-up of June 20, 2018 Meetup</title>
        <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;What a terrific kickoff event! I want to thank the 35 or so attendees for their interaction and some great questions during the presentations and great follow-up afterwards. Thanks to Switch for providing a fantastic room (with very easy AV setup). Big thanks for everyone who told someone else about the event or brought someone along, word-of-mouth is our best (and only) marketing tool!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;There were 3 presentations:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;an introduction to the Python and R languages, for people who are heavy Excel users&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a live coding session in Python where we calculated the concentration of the customer base that generates the bulk of revenue (i.e. the &amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;80&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt;&amp;amp;frasl;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;20&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; rule)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;a short summary of the reasons for starting the group and goals going forward&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The slide decks and the code for 3 presentations are available in the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/18/presentations-20180620.html&amp;#34;&amp;gt;previous post&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We also heard some a little about how casinos measure players&amp;amp;rsquo; theoretical win for table games (as opposed to slots which calculate it automatically), about how video poker machines are often not configured to credit profitable players with an appropriate amount of contribution, and a few past casino promotions and sportsbook odds gone wrong.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Meetup page for this event is &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://www.meetup.com/Casino-Analytics/events/250643391/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;here&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This really was a great first event, glad we got so many people with a variety of backgrounds and experience. Thanks to everyone who offered feedback. Please reach out if you have ideas for a future presentation!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-06-20 23:19:00 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
        <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/20/wrapup-20180620.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/20/wrapup-20180620.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presentations for June 20, 2018 Meetup</title>
        <description>

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Links to the talks that will be presented at the June 20, 2018 Meetup, held at InNEVation Center, Powered by Switch.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;h2 id=&amp;#34;1st-python-and-r-for-excel-pros&amp;#34;&amp;gt;1st: Python and R for Excel Pros&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/documents/presentations/revealjs/excel_python_r.html&amp;#34;&amp;gt;slide deck&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;h2 id=&amp;#34;2nd-python-code-walkthrough-for-80-20-rule-analysis&amp;#34;&amp;gt;2nd: Python code walkthrough for &amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;80&amp;lt;/sup&amp;gt;&amp;amp;frasl;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;20&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; rule analysis&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/documents/jupyter/8020rule.html&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Jupyter notebook&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;h2 id=&amp;#34;3rd-overview-and-goals-for-cap-coop&amp;#34;&amp;gt;3rd: Overview and goals for CAP-COOP&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;/documents/presentations/remarkjs/capcoop.html&amp;#34;&amp;gt;slide deck&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-06-18 14:31:00 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
        <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/18/presentations-20180620.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/18/presentations-20180620.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>June 20 Meetup will be at Innevation Center</title>
        <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Previously, we had announced the first Meetup would be on June 20, but weren&amp;amp;rsquo;t sure where. We are happy to say that the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://www.innevation.com/&amp;#34;&amp;gt;InNEVation Center, Powered by Switch&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; has agreed to host us. The agenda will remain the same: an intro to the group and an introduction to Python and R for data analysis, especially for Excel users.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;We&amp;amp;rsquo;ll start at 6:30, and there will be free food. There is no charge to attend, or reservations required, so we hope you&amp;amp;rsquo;ll bring a colleague along.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The InNEVation Center is located off the 215 &amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/The&#43;Innevation&#43;Center/@36.0665333,-115.2192654,15.75z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x4f1c35e8f68b2e74!8m2!3d36.0666193!4d-115.2136257&amp;#34;&amp;gt;between Decatur and Jones&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-06-16 15:46:00 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
        <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/16/meetup-location-20180620.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/06/16/meetup-location-20180620.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Plan for first meetup</title>
        <description>&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The first CAP-COOP Meetup is tentatively scheduled for June 20, 2018. Our first topic will be an introduction to Python and R for data analysis. If you&amp;amp;rsquo;re someone who relies primarily on Excel, or Tableau, or a BI tool like Cognos for most of your work, this will provide insight to the power of performing data analysis with these languages and hopefully provide some incentive to start learning. We&amp;amp;rsquo;d love to have a second speaker, if you have a topic to discuss or suggest, please reach out via Meetup.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;What topics might we cover in the future? More in-depth Python subjects, SQL tutorials, machine learning introduction, overview of AWS services, discussion of graphing libraries (ggplot, matplotlib, plotly, etc), big-data tools (Hadoop, Spark Kafka), NoSQL and columnar databases. We also hope to cover real-world case studies of projects that members built, and collaborative problem-solving for projects still in progress.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2018-05-14 10:49:00 &#43;0000 UTC</pubDate>
        <link>http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/05/14/first-meetup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://casinoanalytics.org/2018/05/14/first-meetup.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
